Did you ever feel this
你在写小部件内
satisfied writing logic inside your widgets
的逻辑时，有没有感到这种满足？
just because that's how flutter is designed
只是因为这就是飘带的设计方式
If you didn't, don't worry
如果你没有，不要担心
You are still completely normal person
你仍然是一个完全正常的人
and for those of you who did
而对于那些做了的人
what if I told you
如果我告诉你
you can swallow a blue pill and make most of it go away
你可以吞下一颗蓝色的药丸，让它的大部分都消失。
Let me introduce you to Flutter Hooks
让我给你介绍一下翩翩起舞的钩子
Hooks will solve two of your main issues
钩子将解决你的两个主要问题
boilerplate of stateful widget
有状态小组件的模板
and sharing same code across in its state
并在其状态中共享相同的代码
and dispose methods of your widgets
和处置你的小部件的方法
Remember less time
记得更少一些
you have to spend writing and maintaining code
你必须花钱编写和维护代码
means more time for your friends
意味着有更多的时间给你的朋友
family or your girlfriend/boyfriend
家庭或你的女朋友/男朋友
unless you don't have any of those
除非你没有任何这些
then you should just probably skip this video
那么你就应该跳过这个视频
Anyways, let's get started
总之，让我们开始吧
Enter flutter pub
进入翩翩酒馆
get flutter_hooks into a console
获取flutter_hooks进入控制台
and wait for magic to do its work
并等待魔法发挥作用
I promised you getting rid of boilerplates
我答应过你要摆脱模板的。
so let's do that first
所以我们先做这个吧
Replace your stateful widget with stateless widget
用一个无状态的小组件替换你的有状态小组件
and change it into a hook widget
并把它改成一个钩子小部件
If you ever use the React hooks before
如果你以前使用过React钩子的话
you'll probably know what's coming next
你可能就会知道接下来会发生什么了
but for those of you who didn't
但对于那些不知道的人来说
bear with me
忍耐一下吧
Hook is a reusable piece of code
钩子是一段可重复使用的代码
you can write your own hook
你可以写你的钩子
or use one of the many pretty
或者使用软件包中许多相当好的钩子之一
In either case
在任一情况下
there is a rule
有一个规则，
that hook must always be prefixed with use
即钩子必须总是以使用为前缀。
and called only in build method of a widget
并且只在小部件的构建方法中调用
One of the most useful pretty fine hooks is use effect
最有用的相当精细的钩子之一是使用效果
it takes a function as a 1st parameter
它需要一个函数作为第一参数
and gives you an option to return
并让你选择返回另一个函数
another function as a return value
作为返回值
Second parameter is a list of variables which if changed
第二个参数是一个变量列表，如果改变了这些变量
will cause use effect hook to execute again
将导致使用效果钩子再次执行
Leaving 2nd parameter as empty array
将第二个参数保留为空数组
will make sure cold runs only once
将确保冷启动只运行一次
So what we have here is basically in its state
因此，我们在这里所拥有的基本上是它的状态
and disposed without usual boilerplate
并在没有通常的繁文缛节的情况下进行了处置
Let's start the app and convince ourselves
让我们启动应用程序，让自己相信
that is really the case
这是事实
We can also have multiple instances of the same
我们也可以让同一个钩子
hook containing different code
的多个实例包含不同的代码
which is great
这很好
They will both run in the order you define them
它们都将按照你定义的顺序运行。
hooks are basically pieces of
钩子是存储在你的小部件中
codes stored in a list in your widget
的列表中的代码片段
but instead of sharing same state with the widget
但不是与小部件共享相同的状态
each one of them runs in isolation
它们中的每一个都是独立运行的
For that reason
因为这个原因
hooks should never be called in sight conditions
钩子不应该在看到的情况下被调用
and finally, let's see what happens if we change
最后，让我们看看如果我们
variable listed in second parameter
改变第二个参数中列出的变量会发生什么。
Notice that code in
注意，其他使用
other use effect hook didn't get called
效果钩子的代码没有被调用
but the one would change parameter did
但那个会改变参数的人做到了
By now, you must probably be thinking
现在，你一定在想
useEffect is a good place to initialize
使用效果是一个初始化的好地方
and dispose my streams
并处理我的流
text editing controllers
文本编辑控制器
or run any initialization code
或运行任何初始化代码
That is correct
那是正确的
but people from Flutter Hooks community
但来自翩翩钩子社区的人
have foreseen that and created
谈到这个问题的时候，我想说的是，我已经预见到了，并且创造了
more specialized hooks which will make your life even
更加专业的钩子，这将使
more easier
你的生活更加轻松
Another hook you'll probably
另一个你可能会发现很方便的钩子
find handy is used text editing controller
是使用的文本编辑控制器
Text editing controller is one of those resources that
文本编辑控制器是那些需要
need to be created and dispose manually
手动创建和处置的资源之一
but when used as a hook disposing it is automatic
但当作为一个钩子处理时，它是自动的
Also, the bowlerplate of creating stateful widget
另外，创建一个有状态的小部件的模板
just to dispose the
只是为了处理
extending controller is gone
扩展控制器，这种做法已经消失了。
and everything looks more neat and readable
一切看起来都更加整洁和可读
In addition, there are hooks for similar controllers
此外，还有类似控制器的钩子
like tapController, pageController
如 tapController, pageController
and scrollController
和滚动控制器
For example
比如说
if we want to change steps programmatically
如果我们想以编程方式改变步骤
using stepController
使用步骤控制器
this is the
这是我们
code we'd have to write down in order to make it work
必须写下的代码，以使其工作。
We can achieve the same thing
我们可以实现同样的事情
using use step controller hook with far less code
使用步骤控制器钩子，代码少得多
In case, we need to do some initialization
在这种情况下，我们需要做一些初始化工作
like adding a listener to a controller
比如在控制器中添加一个监听器
We can do it inside the use effect hook
我们可以在使用效果的钩子里做这件事
I hope this gives you an idea
我希望这能给你一个想法
how hooks can work together
钩子如何能一起工作
Now, let's move on to use state hook
现在，让我们继续使用状态钩子
use state will require a generic argument
使用状态将需要一个通用参数
which is your initial state
你的初始状态是什么？
This can obviously be any basic type but also an object
这可以是任何基本类型，但也可以是一个物体
For a sake of simplicity
为了简单起见
let's use a boolean state
让我们使用一个布尔状态
which will dog a visibility of an element
这将是一个元素的可见性
when we click on a button
当我们点击一个按钮时
Let's run demo to make sure example works as expected
让我们运行一个演示，以确保该例子如预期那样工作
Clicking on button indeed changes our bullion state
点击按钮确实改变了我们的金币状态
and text elements visibilities changing too
而且文本元素的可见度也会改变
Use state hook is actually a value notifier
使用状态钩是一个值通知器
which means we access its state from the value parameter
这意味着我们从值参数中访问它的状态
This works great
这工作很好
but notice that we are rebuilding hole widget
但是请注意，
for something that actually
我们正在为发生在树中
takes place significantly lower in the tree
明显较低位置的东西重建孔部件
We could easily solve this problem by extracting
我们可以很容易地解决这个问题，
everything under sized box widget to another widget
把所有尺寸不足的盒子小部件提取到另一个小部件上
And this is actually recommended so called flutter way
而这是推荐的所谓飘忽不定的方式
but in some instances, you might not want to do that
但在某些情况下，你可能不希望这样做
Either when widget is too simple like this one
或者是当小部件太简单的时候，比如这个小部件
or for the sake of readability
或者为了可读性的缘故
In that case, you can isolate what gets rebuild
在这种情况下，你可以通过使用一个
by using widget called hook builder
叫做hook builder的小部件来隔离被重建的内容
You can put hook builder anywhere in your tree
你可以在你的树中的任何地方放置钩子构建器
and color hook from its builder method
并从它的构建器方法中给钩子着色
Another way to approach this problem
另一种方法来处理这个问题
is by using use value note to fire hook
是通过使用使用值注释来启动一个钩子
The difference between these two hooks
这两个钩子的区别是
is that use state immediately notifies
是，使用状态会立即通知
or rebuilds when state changes while
或重建，而使用
use value notifier doesn't
值通知器则不会。
This way we can keep state reference in the top widget
这样我们就可以在顶部的小部件中保持状态参考
and rebuild
并重建
only those child widgets which are listening to it
只有那些正在监听它的子部件。
We can listen to changes with use value listenable hook
我们可以通过使用value listenable挂钩来监听变化
Now, let's move to a more realistic example
现在，让我们转到一个更现实的例子
sooner or later you need to access some
迟早你需要用你的
kind of API with your app
应用程序访问某种API
and display the result in your widget
并在你的小部件中显示结果
You hopefully be very uncomfortable
你希望在你的小部件中
with putting that kind of code in your widget
放入这样的代码是非常不舒服的。
and instead create a separate class to honor
而不是创建一个单独的类，
separation of concerns principle
以履行关注点分离的原则
Once you do that
一旦你这样做
you need to call those API functions
你需要在你的widget的某个地方调用
somewhere in your widget
这些API函数
like OnPressed method of a button
就像一个按钮的OnPressed方法
that means you need a reference to API
这意味着你需要一个对
class on a top widget level
顶层小部件上的API类的引用
which can be achieved with used memoized hook
这可以通过使用记忆化钩子来实现
In use memoized hook
在使用记忆化钩子中
you can instantiate your big objects
你可以实例化你的大对象
which are going to be cashed between a visit rebuilds
这将在访问重建之间兑现。
Second parameter
第二个参数
also takes list of values
也需要一个值的列表
which if change
如果改变
it will force new instance of object to be created
它将迫使新的对象实例被创建。
Now, we can use concrete method from our API
现在，我们可以使用我们的
class to fetch some data
API类中的具体方法来获取一些数据了
We'll hook it into a future builder
我们将把它与未来的建造者挂钩
since the method we are calling return's future
因为这个方法，我们正在调用返回未来
When the widget loads
当小组件加载时
so will data from our API call
我们的API调用的数据也会如此
which is great
这很好
What if we want to get
如果我们想在
fresh data at some point in the future?
未来的某个时间点获得新鲜的数据怎么办？
We could store function call
我们可以把函数调用
into a value notifier hook
存储到一个值通知器钩中
and wrap future builder with the hook builder
并将未来的构建器与钩子构建器包裹起来
Those subscribe to changes
那些通过调用
by calling gius value listenable
gius value listenable 来订阅变化的人
and each time there is a change
而且每次都有一个变化
New future will be obtained
就会得到一个新的未来
and best to a future builder
和最好的未来建设者
by assigning same API function called to a value notifier
通过分配相同的API函数调用到一个值通知器上
We are basically triggering a rebuild
我们正在用相同的函数
with the same function but different result
触发一个重建，但结果不同
If you're thinking that's a bit varied workaround
如果你认为这是一个有点变化的变通方法来做一些
to do something simple like
简单的事情，
calling a function
比如调用一个函数
You're right, the thing is
你是对的，事情是
flutter hooks
扇形钩
wasn't meant to be
并不意味着
some sort of state management solution by default
默认情况下会成为某种状态管理的解决方案
The main purpose of this  package
这个软件包的主要目的是
is to increase coach sharing
是为了增加小部件之间
between widgets and reduce boilerplate
的教练共享，减少模板
For that reason
因为这个原因
flutter hooks package is often used with riverpod
Flutter钩子包经常与河港一起使用
Redux
Redux
bloc or any other proper state management packages
bloc 或任何其他适当的状态管理包
There is also a way to do state management
也有一种方法可以进行状态管理
only with flutter hooks
只能用扑朔迷离的钩子
but this will be a topic for the future video
但这将是未来视频的一个主题
One case where hooks shine the most are the animations
钩子最闪亮的一种情况是动画
by now, you have probably
到现在为止，
found yourself in a situation
你可能已经发现自己
where you need a custom animation
处于这样一种情况：
that is not available as one of the existing animation widgets
你需要一个自定义的动画，而这个动画又不能作为现有的动画部件之一使用。
Having that
有了这个
meant turning your previously stateless widget
意味着把你以前的无状态小部件
into a stateful widget
变成一个有状态的小部件
just so you can create and dispose animation controller
这样你就可以创建和处理动画控制器了。
Let's take a look at simple example
让我们看看一个
of record button with animated shadow
简单的例子，一个带有动画阴影的记录按钮
First, we need to define animation controller
首先，我们需要定义动画控制器
and set some duration and direction
并设置一些持续时间和方向
We can store animation object using use memoized hook
我们可以使用memoized钩子来存储动画对象
because there's no need to get new instance of
因为不需要每次都获得一个
resource every time
新的资源实例。
which it rebuilt
这是它重建的
And finally, we'll define recording state
最后，我们将定义录音状态
Now, animation can be assigned to animation builder
现在，可以将动画分
and values to animate shadow
配给动画生成器和值，以使影子动画化
can be obtained from animation object
可以从动画对象中获得
Inside on press method of a button
在一个按钮的内部按下方法
will toggle recording state
将切换录音状态
which will render appropriate icon and shadow
这将呈现适当的图标和阴影
Let's run this game and see if it works
让我们运行这个游戏，看看它是否有效
Clicking on record starts animation and shows stop icon
点击记录启动动画并显示停止图标
just as expected
就像预期的那样
Clicking stop will remove shadow and render record button
点击 "停止 "将删除阴影，并呈现记录按钮
We can expand this example with one more widget
我们可以用另外一个部件来扩展这个例子
Let's suppose we want to display elapsed time
让我们假设我们想显示经过的时间
since recording started
从录音开始
and reset it when recording is stopped
并在停止录制时重置它
to make things more readable
以使事情变得更容易阅读
we'll extract button widget and create new elapsed time
我们将提取按钮部件并创建一个新的
label widget
经过时间标签部件
Since those widgets will both depend on recording state
由于这些小部件都将依赖于记录状态
we can wrap them together with hook builder widget
我们可以用钩子构建器部件把它们包在一起
and pass the state down to their constructors
并将状态传递给它们的构造器
Elapsed time label widget
经过的时间标签小部件
will consist of simple
将由一个简单的
text widget wrapped in visibility widget
文本小部件组成，并包裹在一个可见性小部件中
We can hook recording state value
我们可以钩住记录状态值
to its visibility field
到它的可见性字段
Next thing, we'll need is some kind of timer
下一件事，我们将需要某种定时器
which will periodically update text widget
它将定期更新文本小部件
One important thing we have to keep in mind is
我们必须记住一件重要的事情，那就是
we will have lots of free builds depending on timer
我们将有大量的自由构建，这取决于我们指定的
period we specify
定时器周期
We definitely don't want to rebuild more times than
我们不希望重建的次数超过
maximum frames per second our device can't push
我们设备不能推动的每秒最大帧数
Luckily, there is something called single
幸运的是，有一种叫做单一股票
ticker provider which solves that issue
提供者的东西解决了这个问题
and it's already available as a building hook
而且它已经可以作为一个建筑钩子了
Next, we'll need to create actual ticker object
下一步，我们需要创建一个实际的ticker对象
which will use sticker provider
这将使用一个贴纸提供者
a sticking source
一个粘性源
and update state
和更新状态
after every frame elapses
在每一帧的时间结束后
Now that we have ticker object
现在，我们有了一个股票对象
We also need to make it stick
我们还需要让它坚持下去
We can do that in use effect hook
我们可以在使用效果钩中做到这一点
We'll also have to make sure call this rerun
我们还得确保所有这些重新运行的
after recording state changes by adding recorder.value
值添加到使用效果钩子的依赖列表中，
to the dependency list of use effect hook
以确保在记录状态改变后重新运行。
Sticker should also eventually be disposed
该贴纸最终也应被处理掉
so we will need another use effect hook
所以我们将需要另一个使用效果钩
and make sure it runs only once and only own disposed
并确保它只运行一次，而且只由自己处理。
Now we have all resourcess ready
现在我们已经准备好了所有的资源
So let's block state to the text widget and run example
所以，让我们把状态封锁给文本部件，并运行这个例子
You might have noticed that
你可能已经注意到
we had to write a bit more code to make all this work
我们不得不多写一点代码来使这一切正常进行
which made our widget filled with logic
这使得我们的小部件充满了逻辑
Last thing we want to do is
我们想做的最后一件事是
defy all the principles we were fighting
违背了我们在战斗中使用飘带钩的
using flutter hooks
所有原则
but fear not my friends
但不要害怕，我的朋友们
because we can extract all the logic
因为我们可以将所有的逻辑提取到
into a custom hook in a separate file
一个单独的文件中的自定义钩子中。
Creating custom hook couldn't be easier
创建一个自定义钩子再简单不过了
All you have to do is create function
你所要做的就是创建一个函数
and copy out the logic inside it
并复制出它里面的逻辑
Make sure your hook name starts with use
确保你的钩子名称以我们开头
and returns resource you are interested to
并返回你感兴趣的资源
In this case, we'll return duration
在这种情况下，我们将返回持续时间
Now we can replace all of our code in widget build method
现在，我们可以用一行来替换我们
with only one line
在 widget build 方法中的所有代码
Also, you can use the hook in
另外，如果你需要的话，
any other widget if you need to
你可以在任何其他小部件中使用这个钩子
and that's it folks
就这样吧，伙计们
Enjoy your fish
享受你美好的一天